When I've been building applications with large language models,
当我使用大型语言模型构建应用程序时，
I don't think I've ever come to the prompt that I ended up
我不认为我在最终应用程序中使用的提示
using in the final application on my first attempt.
就是我第一次尝试中使用的提示
And this isn't what matters.
这并不重要。
As long as you have a good process to iteratively make your prompt better,
只要您有一个不断改进提示的良好过程，
then you'll be able to come to something that
那么您就能够
works well for the task you want to achieve.
很好地完成您想要实现的任务的东西。
You may have heard me say that when I create a machine learning model,
您可能听我说过，当我创建一个机器学习模型时，
it almost never works the first time.
第一次几乎从来不会成功。
In fact, I'm very surprised that the first model I trained works.
事实上，我对我训练的第一个模型能够工作感到非常惊讶。
I think we're prompting, the odds of it working the first time is
我认为我们在提示，它第一次工作的几率
maybe a little bit higher but as Isa was saying,
可能有点高，但正如Isa所说的那样，
doesn't matter if the first prompt works,
第一个提示是否有效并不重要，
what matters most is the process for
最重要的是为了
getting to the prompts that works for your application.
找到适用于您的应用程序的提示的过程。
So with that, let's jump into the code and let me show you
那么，让我们进入代码，让我向您展示
some frameworks to think about how to iteratively develop a prompt.
一些关于如何迭代开发提示的框架。
So if you've taken a machine learning class with me before,
所以，如果您之前上过我的机器学习课程，
you may have seen me use a diagram saying that with machine learning development,
您可能看过我用一个图表表示，在机器学习开发中，
you often have an idea and then implement it.
您通常会有一个想法，然后实现它。
So write the code, get the data,
所以编写代码，获取数据，
train your model, and that gives you an experimental result.
训练您的模型，这会给您一个实验结果。
And you can then look at that output,
然后您可以查看那个输出，
maybe do error analysis,
也许进行错误分析，
figure out where it's working or not working,
找出它哪里有效或无效，
and then maybe even change your idea of
也许甚至改变您的想法
exactly what problem you want to solve or how to approach it.
关于您想解决的问题或如何解决它。
And then change, implementation and run
然后改变、实现并运行
another experiment and so on and iterate over and over
另一个实验等等，反复进行
to get to an effective machine learning model.
以获得一个有效的机器学习模型。
If you're not familiar with machine learning,
如果您不熟悉机器学习，
haven't seen this diagram before, don't worry about it,
之前没有看过这个图表，不用担心，
not that important for the rest of this presentation.
对于本演示的其余部分并不那么重要。
But when you are writing prompts to develop an application using an LLM,
但是，当您使用LLM编写提示以开发应用程序时，
the process can be quite similar,
这个过程可能非常相似，
where you have an idea for what you want to do,
您有一个关于您想要做什么的想法，
the task you want to complete,
您想要完成的任务，
and you can then take a first attempt at writing
然后您可以尝试第一次编写
a prompt that hopefully is clear and specific,
一个希望是清晰和具体的提示，
and maybe if appropriate,
也许在适当的情况下，
gives the system time to think.
给系统时间去思考。
And then you can run it and see what result you get.
然后您可以运行它，看看您得到什么结果。
And if it doesn't work well enough the first time,
如果第一次效果不够好，
then the iterative process of figuring out why the instructions,
那么弄清楚为什么指令的迭代过程，
for example, were not clear enough,
不够清晰，
or why it didn't give the algorithm enough time to think,
或者为什么没有给算法足够的时间去思考，
allows you to refine the idea,
这可以让您优化想法，
refine the prompt, and so on,
优化提示等等，
and to go around this loop multiple times,
多次循环这个过程，
until you end up with a prompt that works for your application.
直到您得到一个适用于您应用的提示。
This too is why I personally have not paid as much attention
这也是为什么我个人没有那么关注
to the internet articles that say 30 perfect prompts,
那些声称有30个完美提示的互联网文章，
because I think there probably isn't a perfect prompt for everything under the sun.
因为我认为可能并不存在适用于所有场景的完美提示。
It's more important that you have a process for
更重要的是，您需要有一个过程，
developing a good prompt for your specific application.
为您特定的应用开发一个好的提示。
So let's look at an example together in code.
那么让我们一起在代码中看一个例子。
I have here the starter code that you saw in the previous videos,
我这里有之前视频中看到的入门代码，
have been port openAI and import os.
已经导入了openAI和import os。
Here we get the openAI API key,
这里我们获取openAI API密钥，
and this is the same helper function that you saw as last time.
这是您上次看到的相同的辅助函数。
And I'm going to use as the running example in this video,
在这个视频中，我将使用一个运行示例，
the task of summarizing a fact sheet for a chair.
任务是为一把椅子的资料页进行总结。
So let me just paste that in here.
让我把它粘贴在这里。
And feel free to pause the video and read
请随时暂停视频并阅读
this more carefully in the notebook on the left if you want.
如果您愿意，可以在左侧的笔记本中仔细阅读这个。
But here's a fact sheet for a chair with a description saying it's part of
这里有一张椅子的资料页，描述说它是
a beautiful family of mid-century inspired and so on.
一个美丽的中世纪风格家族的一部分，等等。
Talks about the construction, has the dimensions,
谈论了结构，有尺寸，
options for the chair, materials, and so on.
椅子的选项、材料等等。
Comes from Italy. So let's say you want to take
产自意大利。那么假设您想
this fact sheet and help a marketing team write
拿着这份资料页，帮助市场营销团队撰写
a description for an online retail website.
一份在线零售网站的描述。
Let me just quickly run these three and then we'll come up with a prompt as follows.
让我快速运行这三个，然后我们将会有如下提示。
And I'll just paste this in.
我只需粘贴这个。
So my prompt here says,
所以我的提示是，
your task is to help a marketing team create
您的任务是帮助市场营销团队创建
a description for a retail website or product based on a techno fact sheet,
基于一份技术性的资料页，为零售网站或技术信息表，
write a product description, and so on.
编写一份产品描述等等。
So this is my first attempt to explain the task to the large language model.
所以这是我第一次尝试向大型语言模型解释任务。
So let me hit Shift+Enter.
那么让我按Shift+Enter。
And this takes a few seconds to run.
这需要几秒钟的运行时间。
And we get this result.
然后我们得到了这个结果。
It looks like it's done a nice job writing a description,
看起来它完成了一个很好的描述工作，
introducing a stunning mid-century inspired office chair,
介绍了一款令人惊叹的中世纪风格办公椅，
perfect addition, and so on.
完美的补充，等等。
But when I look at this, I go, boy, this is really long.
但当我看到这个时，我想，这真的很长。
It's done a nice job doing exactly what I asked it to,
它确实很好地完成了我要求它做的事情，
which is start from the technical fact sheet and write a product description.
也就是从技术资料页开始，撰写产品描述。
But when I look at this, I go, this is kind of long.
但当我看到这儿时，我想，这有点长。
Maybe we want it to be a little bit shorter.
也许我们希望它稍微短一点。
So I have had an idea.
所以我有了一个想法。
I wrote a prompt, got a result.
我写了一个提示，得到了一个结果。
I'm not that happy with it because it's too long.
我对它不是很满意，因为它太长了。
So I will then clarify my prompt and say,
所以我会明晰我的提示，写道，
use at most 50 words to try to give
尝试用最多50个单词来给出
better guidance on the desired length of this and let's run it again.
关于这个所需长度的更好指导。让我们再次运行它。
Okay, this actually looks like a much nicer short description of the product,
好的，这实际上看起来是一个更好的简短产品描述，
introducing a mid-century inspired office chair, and so on.
介绍了一款中世纪风格的办公椅，等等。
Five wheel base yeah,
五个轮子支撑...，是的，
both stylish and practical. Not bad.
既时尚又实用。还不错。
And let me double-check the length that this is.
让我再次检查一下这个回答的长度。
So I'm going to take the response,
所以我要把这个回答
split it according to where the space is,
根据空格的位置进行分割，
and then, you know, print out the length.
然后，您知道的，打印出长度。
So it's 52 words.
所以是52个单词。
Actually, not bad.
实际上，还不错。
Large language models are okay,
大型语言模型还可以，
but not that great at following instructions about a very precise word count.
但它还不太擅长遵循非常精确的字数要求。
But this is actually not bad.
但这实际上还不错啦。
Sometimes it will print out something with 60 or 65 and so on words,
有时它会打印出60或65个字数长度的内容，
but it's kind of within reason.
但这在合理范围内。
Some of the things you could try to do would be,
您可以尝试做的一些事情包括，
um, to say use at most three sentences.
嗯，最多使用三个句子。
Let me run that again.
让我再试一次。
But these are different ways to tell the large language model
但这些都是不同的方法来告诉大型语言模型
what's the length of the output that you want.
您想要的输出长度是多少。
So this is 1, 2, 3.
所以，1，2，3，
I count three sentences.
我数了以下有三个句子。
Looks like I did a pretty good job.
看起来我做得很好。
And then I've also seen people sometimes do things like,
然后我也看到人们有时会做类似的事情，比如
I don't know, use at most 280 characters.
我不知道，最多使用280个字符。
Large language models, because of the way they interpret text,
由于大型语言模型解释文本的方式，
using something called a tokenizer,
使用一种叫做分词器的东西，
which- which I won't talk about.
这个我就不在此细说了，
But, um, they tend to be so-so at counting characters.
但是，呃，它们在计算字符方面表现很一般。
But let's see, 281 characters.
但让我们看看，281个字符。
It's actually surprisingly close.
实际上已经出奇地接近。
Usually a large language model is- doesn't get it quite this close.
通常，大型语言模型无是法做到这么接近的。
But these are different ways that you can play with to try to
但这些是您可以尝试的不同方法，
control the length of the output that you get.
控制您得到的输出长度。
But let me just switch it back to use at most 50 words.
但是，让我再把它切换回最多使用50个单词。
And there's that result that we had just now.
这就是我们刚才得到的结果。
As we continue to refine this text for our websites,
当我们继续为我们的网站优化这段文字时，
we might decide that, boy,
我们可能会决定，哇，
this website isn't selling direct to consumers,
这个网站并不是直接面向消费者销售的，
it's actually intended to sell furniture to furniture retailers
实际上，它是为了向家具零售商销售家具，
that would be more interested in
他们会更感兴趣
the technical details of the chair and the materials of the chair.
椅子的技术细节和椅子的材质。
In that case, you can take this prompt and say,
在这种情况下，您可以采用这个提示，
I want to modify this prompt to get it to be more precise about the technical details.
我想修改这个提示，让它在技术细节上更精确。
So let me keep on modifying this prompt.
所以让我继续修改这个提示。
And I'm going to say, this description is intended for furniture retailers,
我要说的是，这个描述是为家具零售商准备的，
so it should be technical and focus on materials,
所以它应该更偏向于技术性，关注材质，
products and constructed from.
产品和构造。
Well, let's run that.
好的，让我们运行它。
And let's see.
让我们看看结果。
Not bad, says, you know,
不错，您知道，
coated aluminum base and pneumatic chair, high quality materials.
涂层铝基座和气动椅，高质量材料。
So by changing the prompt,
所以，通过改变提示，
you can get it to focus more on specific characters,
您可以让它更关注特定内容，
on specific characteristics you wanted to.
在您想要的特定特征上。
And when I look at this,
当我看到这个时，
I might decide at the end of the description,
我可能会决定在描述的最后，
I also wanted to include the product IDs.
我还想加上产品ID，
So the two offerings of this chair,
椅子的两个产品ID，
SWC 110, SWC 100.
So maybe I can further improve this prompt.
所以也许我可以进一步改进这个提示。
And to get it to give me the product IDs,
为了让它帮我加上产品ID，
I can add this instruction at the end of the description,
我可以在描述的末尾添加这个指令，
include every seven character product ID in the technical specification.
在技术规格中，用7个字符的列出每个产品ID。
And let's run it and see what happens.
让我们运行它，看看会发生什么。
And so it says, introduce you to our mid-century inspired office chair,
所以它说，向您介绍我们的中世纪风格办公椅，
shell colors, talks about plastic coating, aluminum base,
外壳颜色，提到了塑料涂层，铝基座，
practical, some options,
实用性，一些选项，
talks about the two product IDs.
提到了两个产品ID。
So this looks pretty good.
所以这看起来很不错。
And what you've just seen is a short example of the iterative
您刚刚看到的简短示例是一个
prompt development that many developers will go through.
许多开发者都会经历的提示开发迭代过程。
And I think a guideline is in the last video you saw
上一个视频中，有一个指导原则，
Isa share a number of best practices.
Isa分享了一些最佳实践。
And so what I usually do is keep best practices like that in mind,
我通常做的就是记住这些最佳实践，
be clear and specific, and if necessary,
要清晰明确，如果有必要，
give the model time to think.
给模型时间去思考。
With those in mind, it's worthwhile to often take a first attempt at writing a prompt,
牢记于心，经常编写提示时第一次尝试是值得的。
see what happens, and then go from there to iteratively refine the prompt to get
看看会发生什么，然后从那里开始迭代，优化提示，
closer and closer to the results that you need.
越来越接近您需要的结果。
And so a lot of the successful prompts that you may see using various programs
因此，您可能会在各种各样的程序中看到，许多成功的提示，
was arrived at at an iterative process like this.
是通过像这样的迭代过程得到的。
Just for fun, let me show you an example of a even more complex prompt that might
仅供娱乐，让我给您展示一个更复杂的提示示例，
give you a sense of what chat GPT can do,
让您感受一下ChatGPT的功能，
which is I've just added a few extra instructions here.
我在这里添加了一些额外的指示
After the description, include a table that gives the product dimensions,
在描述之后，包含一个展示产品尺寸的表格，
and then you'll format everything as HTML.
然后将所有输出内容格式化为HTML。
So let's run that.
那我们来运行一下。
And in practice, you end up with a prompt like this,
实际操作中，您最终会得到类似这样的提示，
really only after multiple iterations.
确实只有在多次迭代之后才能实现。
I don't think I know anyone that would write this exact prompt the first time
我不认为我认识的任何人能在第一次就写出这么准确的提示，
they were trying to get the system to process a fact sheet.
当他们尝试让系统处理一份资料页时。
And so this actually outputs a bunch of HTML.
所以这实际上输出了一堆HTML。
Let's display the HTML to see if this is even valid HTML and see if this works.
让我们显示HTML，看看这是否是有效的HTML，看看这是否有效。
And I don't actually know it's going to work, but let's see.
我实际上并不知道它会不会起作用，但让我们看看。
Oh, cool.
哦，酷。
All right, looks like it rendered.
好的，看起来它渲染成功了。
So it has this really nice looking description of a chair.
所以它是一个非常漂亮的椅子描述。
Construction, materials, product dimensions.
结构，材料，产品尺寸。
Oh, it looks like I left out the use at most 50 words instruction.
哦，看起来我遗漏了最多使用50个单词的指令。
So this is a little bit long, but if you want that, you can even--
所以这有点长，但如果您愿意，您甚至可以——
feel free to pause the video.
随时暂停视频。
Tell it to be more succinct and regenerate this and see what results you get.
告诉它更简洁地重新生成这个，并查看您得到的结果。
So I hope you take away from this video that prompt development
因此，我希望您从这个视频中了解到提示开发
is an iterative process.
是一个迭代过程。
Try something.
尝试一些事情。
See how it does not yet fulfill exactly what you want.
看看它是否还不能完全满足你的需求。
And then think about how to clarify your instructions, or in some cases,
然后想想如何阐明您的指示，或者在某些情况下，
think about how to give it more space to think
考虑如何给它更多的思考空间
to get it closer to delivering the results that you want.
让它更接近您想要的结果。
And I think the key to being an effective prompt engineer isn't so much
我认为成为一名有效的提示工程师的关键并不是
about knowing the perfect prompt.
了解完美的提示。
It's about having a good process to develop prompts that
而是拥有一个良好的过程来开发
are effective for your application.
对您的应用程序有效的提示。
And in this video, I illustrated developing a prompt using just one example.
在这个视频中，我用一个例子说明了如何开发一个提示，
For more sophisticated applications, sometimes you
对于更复杂的应用程序，有时您会
will have multiple examples, say a list of 10 or even 50 or 100 fact sheets,
有多个示例，比如10个、甚至50个或100个资料页，
and iteratively develop a prompt and evaluate it
并反复开发提示并评估它，
against a large set of cases.
针对大量的案例。
But for the early development of most applications,
但对于大多数应用程序的早期开发，
I see many people developing it sort of the way I am with just one example.
我看到很多人像我这样只用一个示例来开发。
But then for more mature applications, sometimes it
但对于更成熟的应用程序，有时候，
could be useful to evaluate prompts against a larger set of examples,
评估更多示例中的提示可能是有用的，
such as to test different prompts on dozens of fact sheets
比如在几十个资料页上测试不同的提示，
to see how is average or worst case performance is on multiple fact sheets.
查看在多个资料页上的平均或最差性能如何。
But usually, you end up doing that only when an application is more mature,
但通常，只有在应用程序更加成熟时，您才会这么做，
and you have to have those metrics to drive that incremental last few steps
您必须拥有这些指标来推动这些增量的最后几步，
of prompt improvement.
以改进提示。
So with that, please do play with the Jupyter Code Notebook examples
所以，请尝试使用 Jupyter Code Notebook示例，
and try out different variations and see what results you get.
尝试不同的修改，看看您能得到什么结果。
And when you're done, let's go on to the next video, where
完成后，我们继续下一个视频，
we'll talk about one very common use of large language
我们将讨论大型语言模型在软件应用中的一个非常常见的用途，
models in software applications, which is to summarize text.
即在软件应用中对文本进行总结。
So when you're ready, let's go on to the next video.
所以准备好后，让我们继续下一个视频。